{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Declare the following statement?\r\n\"An array of three pointers to chars\".", "opta": "char *ptr[3]();", "optb": "char *ptr[3];", "optc": "char (*ptr[3])();", "optd": "char **ptr[3];", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What do the following declaration signify?\nint *ptr[30];", "opta": "ptr is a pointer to an array of 30 integer pointers.", "optb": "ptr is a array of 30 pointers to integers.", "optc": "ptr is a array of 30 integer pointers.", "optd": "ptr is a array 30 pointers.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Declare the following statement?\r\n\"A pointer to an array of three chars\".", "opta": "char *ptr[3]();", "optb": "char (*ptr)*[3];", "optc": "char (*ptr[3])();", "optd": "char (*ptr)[3];", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What do the following declaration signify?\nchar *arr[10];", "opta": "arr is a array of 10 character pointers.", "optb": "arr is a array of function pointer.", "optc": "arr is a array of characters.", "optd": "arr is a pointer to array of characters.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What do the following declaration signify?\nint (*pf)();", "opta": "pf is a pointer to function.", "optb": "pf is a function pointer.", "optc": "pf is a pointer to a function which return int", "optd": "pf is a function of pointer variable.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Declare the following statement?\n\"A pointer to a function which receives an int pointer and returns float pointer\".", "opta": "float *(ptr)*int;", "optb": "float *(*ptr)(int)", "optc": "float *(*ptr)(int*)", "optd": "float (*ptr)(int)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What do the following declaration signify?\nvoid *cmp();", "opta": "cmp is a pointer to an void type.", "optb": "cmp is a void type pointer variable.", "optc": "cmp is a function that return a void pointer.", "optd": "cmp function returns nothing.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Declare the following statement?\n\"A pointer to a function which receives nothing and returns nothing\".", "opta": "void *(ptr)*int;", "optb": "void *(*ptr)()", "optc": "void *(*ptr)(*)", "optd": "void (*ptr)()", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What do the following declaration signify?\r\nint *f();", "opta": "f is a pointer variable of function type.", "optb": "f is a function returning pointer to an int.", "optc": "f is a function pointer.", "optd": "f is a simple declaration of pointer variable.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What do the following declaration signify?\nvoid (*cmp)();", "opta": "cmp is a pointer to an void function type.", "optb": "cmp is a void type pointer function.", "optc": "cmp is a function that return a void pointer.", "optd": "cmp is a pointer to a function which returns void .", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What do the following declaration signify?\nchar **argv;", "opta": "argv is a pointer to pointer.", "optb": "argv is a pointer to a char pointer.", "optc": "argv is a function pointer.", "optd": "argv is a member of function pointer.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What do the following declaration signify?\nchar *scr;", "opta": "scr is a pointer to pointer variable.", "optb": "scr is a function pointer.", "optc": "scr is a pointer to char.", "optd": "scr is a member of function pointer.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}